Vatan singh

I am a cybersecurity expert with experience in web application testing, network penetration testing and bug bounty hunting. I have found multiple bugs on different organization's assets which helped them in improving their security posture. I am also an active member of various online hacking communities which helps me in keeping my skills up to date

Contact

Haryana, Gurgaon - 122001 Vatansingh688@gmail.com +91-8451-990648 https://github.com/Anonymous4 712

Work Experience

Associate L1, Publicis Sapient

Jul 2023 - Present

- Managed Security Operations Center (SOC) tickets, ensuring prompt and effective resolution of incidents
- Monitored and analyzed security alerts and logs to identify and mitigate potential threats.
- Provided incident handling and response, working to quickly resolve security incidents and minimize impact.
- Familiarity with common cyber threats, attack techniques, and mitigation strategies.

IT Helpdesk, Egon Zehnder

Jan 2023 - Jul 2023

- Provided technical support to users, resolving hardware, software, and network issues.
- Manage user accounts, permissions, and access rights in Active Directory and other IT systems.
- Troubleshoot network connectivity problems and assist in resolving network-related issues.
- Provide training and guidance to end-users on IT systems, software applications, and best

IT Support specialist, NetAccess

Mar 2022 - Jan 2023

- Provided technical support to users, resolving hardware, software, and network issues.
- Assisted in setting up and maintaining IT infrastructure for the client.
- Managed Outlook 365 configurations, including OST/PST backups and restorations.
- Conducted regular system updates and maintenance to ensure optimal performance.

Educational Background

Bachelor In computer Application (BCA) In Cybersecurity

University of Tilak Maharashtra, Mumbai Aug 2019 - Jun 2023

· Specialization in Cybersecurity.

Skills

Technical Skills

- · Penetration Testing
- · Vulnerability Assessment
- Web application security
- · Incident Response
- Ethical Hacking

Tools/Sofware

- Nmap
- Hydra
- Metasploit
- Burp suite
- OpenVas /Linux
- · John The Ripper
- · Bash Scripting

Languages

- English (Fluent)
- Hindi (Fluent)
- Marathi (Average)

Certification/Short Courses

- · Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH)
- Ethical Hacking essential(EHE)
- Certified in Cybersecurity (Isc2)

ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded by
 IBSAR College for achieving first place in Bug Hunting
 Competition

Cloud Security Challenge:
Capture the Cloud (Jul 2024)

Personal Projects

Case study

Completed caste study on how to perform internal network penetration testing on an ip range which is potentially infected with Buffer overflow attack.